another example of prefetching would be
the so-called Hardware prefetching where
the program doesn't change and the
hardware itself either the processor or
the cache is trying to guess what will
be accessed soon there are a number of
Hardware preatures that work reasonably
well for example many current processors
include what's called a stream buffer
prefecture other popular types of
prefectures include a stride prefecture
and what is called a correlating
prefecture all of these try to guess
what is going to be accessed next based
on some sort of locality property so a
stream buffer is sequential in nature
it's trying to see whether once we
access a block and then the next block
that follows it we are likely to access
the next next block and so on so it's
just trying to fetch several blocks in
advance in order to not be too late a
stride based prefecture is monitoring
accesses to see if memory accesses that
we doing are at a fixed distance from
each other so if their addresses differ
by the same amount it's going to guess
that we will just continue doing that
and it starts prefetching with a
distance of D * something and it
determines how many of these in advance
such that it's just in time a
correlating prefecture is trying to
predict sequences of axises that are not
sequential or at the same distance from
each other the way it does this is when
we see a and then B
accessed it remembers in some sort of a
table that when a comes then B comes
then when C comes it remembers that
after B comes C and so on and then later
on if we see a it's going to look here
and issue a prefet for B if we do access
B it's going to look here and issue a
prefetch for C and so on so it can fetch
an arbitrary sequence of accesses as
long as that sequence repeats so it's
very good for example for link list
which are not necessarily sequential in
memory and they're not at fixed
sides but if you access the first node
and the second node at the turn node and
then you do that again it's going to
prefetch correctly